<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Newman</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack Newman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dating a medieval court roll</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dating-a-medieval-court-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dating-a-medieval-court-roll/</guid>
      <description>The previous post was spent learning the basics of text mining and exploring some possible avenues for analysis. In this post I label each offence with as precise a date as possible. In future I will also label it according to particular categories. I can do the first by extracting days, month, or years from the text to new columns and the pairing these with the original text. Essentially the text of the trials is broken into smaller observations and sorted according to particular criteria, in thie case, dates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dating a medieval court roll </title>
      <link>/post/dating-a-medieval-court-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dating-a-medieval-court-roll/</guid>
      <description>Dating the rollThe previous post was spent learning the basics of text mining and exploring some possible avenues for analysis. In this post I label each offence with as precise a date as possible. In future I will also label it according to particular categories. I can do the first by extracting days, month, or years from the text to new columns and the pairing these with the original text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text mining Lincolnshire</title>
      <link>/portfolio/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 22:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/test/</guid>
      <description>I was really looking forward to giving a paper at the International Medieval Congress at Leeds this year on text mining medieval court records on session 836 which was organised by Dr Claire Kennan and Dr Emma J. Wells. I had intended to use the process as an excuse to learn text mining using R. I thought it might be provide some material for my thesis and I am quite evangelical about the possibilities of text mining historical documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cv/</guid>
      <description>Royal Historical Society Centenary Fellow affiliated with the Institute for Historical Research and the Centre for Medieval and Early Modern Studies at the University of Kent.
EducationUniversity of KentCHASE AHRC Funded Ph.D. Medieval and Early Modern Studies (2016-2020).Provisional Title: Corruption and Conflict: Institutional adaptation in pre-Black Death England (c.1307-1348). Supervisors: Professor Barbara Bombi and Dr Ryan Perry.MA Medieval and Early Modern Studies (Distinction - 2015-2016).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>